<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Information Design | Jantsje Mol</title>
    <link>https://www.jantsje.nl/tag/information-design/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://www.jantsje.nl/tag/information-design/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Information Design</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Jantsje Mol © 2025</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://www.jantsje.nl/images/icon_hu7859828887360647904.png</url>
      <title>Information Design</title>
      <link>https://www.jantsje.nl/tag/information-design/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Increasing trackpilot information load</title>
      <link>https://www.jantsje.nl/project/trackpilot-information-load/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jantsje.nl/project/trackpilot-information-load/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3&gt; Measuring situational awareness onboard and ashore under increasing trackpilot information load  &lt;/h3&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;With 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.hogeschoolrotterdam.nl/onderzoek/lectoren/coe-hrtech/lectoren/verduijn-thierry/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Thierry Verduijn&lt;/a&gt;, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/monique-van-der-drift-65908399/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Monique van der Drift&lt;/a&gt; and 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/andreea-s-pop-34b24970/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Andreea Pop&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Abstract:&lt;/b&gt;
Trackpilots can help inland shippers sail an optimal route with minimal human input, which has the potential to save fuel costs and human attention. In theory, widespread adoption of trackpilots is not only beneficial for crew on board, but also for traffic operators ashore, for example by minimizing verbal communication which could allow operators to focus on the most important safety concerns. However, a larger information load in the form of trackpilot data may not necessarily increase situational awareness. This paper examines the effect of trackpilots on situational awareness in practice, with two field experiments run by students of the Rotterdam University of Applied Sciences. The exploratory results suggest that a trackpilot has a positive effect on situational awareness and decreases workload on board. At the same time, when vessel traffic services (VTS) operators ashore receive trackpilot information, situational awareness is unaffected, but operators expect the workload to increase. Policy implications and suggestions for further research are discussed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[analysis phase]&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Information design in one-sided matching problems</title>
      <link>https://www.jantsje.nl/project/task-matching/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jantsje.nl/project/task-matching/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3&gt; For the &#39;Greater Good&#39;: Please Choose A&lt;/h3&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;With 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.lenkafiala.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Lenka Fiala&lt;/a&gt; and 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://sites.google.com/view/sulagna/home?authuser=0&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Sulagna Dasgupta&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Abstract:&lt;/b&gt;
How do people trade off individual versus group welfare in the face of uncertainty regarding private benefits of different actions? We propose a partial information revelation (`recommendation&amp;rsquo;) policy  designed to maximize group welfare, and we show its theoretical robustness to well-documented behavioral deviations from the risk neutral, Bayesian, and self-interested benchmark. In a large-scale online experiment with 2600 subjects, we then show that this policy fails to improve upon a full information benchmark even when individual and group objectives are aligned. In this case, information design is theoretically powerful but requires sophisticated inferences from players. Indeed, we show that cognitive limitations reduce the predictive value of the theory. This provides suggestive evidence in favor of simplicity in information design in multi-agent strategic settings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[in review]&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
