<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Willful ignorance | Jantsje Mol</title>
    <link>https://www.jantsje.nl/tag/willful-ignorance/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://www.jantsje.nl/tag/willful-ignorance/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Willful ignorance</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Jantsje Mol © 2023</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2022 09:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://www.jantsje.nl/images/icon_hue4a4de327998694cb345fdb70473462a_27719_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Willful ignorance</title>
      <link>https://www.jantsje.nl/tag/willful-ignorance/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Supply of willful ignorance</title>
      <link>https://www.jantsje.nl/project/the-button/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2022 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jantsje.nl/project/the-button/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3&gt; Spoiling the Party: Experimental Evidence on the Willingness to Transmit Inconvenient Ethical Information &lt;/h3&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;With 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://sites.google.com/site/ivansoraperra/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Ivan Soraperra&lt;/a&gt; and 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.joelvanderweele.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Joël van der Weele&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Abstract:&lt;/b&gt;
Many people would rather not tell their friends that their decisions can negatively affect a third party, for example by explaining the environmental harm of meat consumption. This paper examines under which circumstances people are willing to interfere by sharing or hiding information: in other words, the supply of willful ignorance. We use a simple online experiment to explore three possible concerns in this situation: own payoffs, charity payoffs and concerns about the decision maker. We developed a new two-person sender-receiver game in which the Receiver decides between a default option with zero payoffs for self and charity, versus a button click which yields a positive payoff to self, but uncertain payoffs for charity. Senders can send a message with the true value of charity payoff, or suppress such inconvenient information to ‘help’ decision makers staying ignorant. We measure the impact of the three concerns and their relationships with different treatments in a large (N = 1512) pre-registered online experiment, controlling for charity preference and the size of the externality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[manuscript in preparation]&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meat opinions</title>
      <link>https://www.jantsje.nl/project/meat-opinions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jantsje.nl/project/meat-opinions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3&gt; Meat opinions - Exploring unconscious reasons for resistance towards a plant-based diet  &lt;/h3&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;With 
&lt;a href=&#34;www.meikemorren.com&#34;&gt;Meike Morren&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Abstract:&lt;/b&gt;
Despite the increased availability of plant-based products, a large group of consumers eats meat and dairy every day, unaware of the impact on environment and health. Increasing awareness is important, but ineffective without procedural knowledge (such as recipes) on how to change this diet. Furthermore, the global challenge to provide sustainable food security to a growing population cannot be tackled by a focus on consumers who are already transitioning to a plant-based diet. This project targets the heaviest meat-eaters and tests the most effective way to make them part of the solution. Despite the evident benefits, many people do not even consider changing to a plant-based diet and meat, dairy and egg consumption continues to increase worldwide. These consumers likely ignore information as it does not align with their beliefs. 
We will obtain insights into the origins of resistance towards a plant-based diet using in-depth interviews and text mining of blogs, pod casts and internet forums. We will gather podcast transcripts, reviews and remarks about meat versus plant-based diets posed on fora such as Quora through web scraping. This way, we will create a database of texts (i.e. referred to as documents) in which the underlying resistance towards a plant-based diet is discussed openly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, we will identify the topics being discussed repeatedly across the collected documents using an unsupervised machine learning model such as Latent Dirichlet Allocation (Blei et al., 2003). LDA allows us to gather topics that are mentioned in multiple documents. Next, using advanced natural language processing models, such as BERT (Devlin et al., 2018), and recent advances such as GoEmotions (Demszky et al., 2021) we will attempt to discover the emotions underlying a resistance towards a plant-based diet. Finally, we will survey the general population to examine the interplay of current diet, emotions and arguments for underlying resistance to transition to a plant-based diet. We will apply a novel method that we recently developed to measure actual environmental impacts of current diet (Morren et al., 2021). This method is suitable for internet-based surveys in the general population.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our research aims to explain why certain people resist a plant-based diet. As meat-eaters are responsible for a large share of environmental impacts, there is a lot to be gained. We will deliver specific recommendations to policy makers about the most promising type of message to encourage heavy meat-eaters to transition to a plant-based diet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[in data collection phase]&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Information about changes in platform economy taxation</title>
      <link>https://www.jantsje.nl/project/trustpath/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jantsje.nl/project/trustpath/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3&gt; Information about changes in platform economy taxation diminishes optimism regarding future use
 &lt;/h3&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;With 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://catherinemolho.github.io/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Catherine Molho&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Abstract:&lt;/b&gt;
Some economic interactions are based on trust, others on monetary incentives or monitoring. In the tax compliance context, the monitoring approach creates compliance based on audits and fines (enforced compliance), in contrast to the trust-based (voluntary compliance) approach, which is based on taxpayers’ willingness to comply. In both approaches, taxpayers’ trust in authorities is relevant. Here, we examine changes in taxation regarding platform economy revenues. Currently, in some European countries this taxation is entirely trust-based, and trade on those platforms prospers. New EU legislation, introduced in 2023, will mandate data sharing between platforms and tax authorities across Europe. As a result, the taxation of platform economy revenues will shift from voluntary compliance into enforced compliance. How would this shift affect the intended use of platforms? We use a survey among platform workers (N = 626) in the Netherlands to examine views of the proposed regulation change, corrected for the proportion of platform income and several measures of trust. We experimentally manipulate information by either informing participants about the upcoming change or not. Results show that informing respondents about the change negatively affects expected supply of labor, mainly among women and part-time workers. The policy implications of these results are discussed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[in review]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See also the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://behavioralethics.org/project/trustpath/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Behavioral Ethics project website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Psychological Science for a Responsible Sharing Economy</title>
      <link>https://www.jantsje.nl/publication/shalvi-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jantsje.nl/publication/shalvi-2021/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
