<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Flood preparedness | Jantsje Mol</title>
    <link>/tag/flood-preparedness/</link>
      <atom:link href="/tag/flood-preparedness/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Flood preparedness</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Jantsje Mol © 2020</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/images/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Flood preparedness</title>
      <link>/tag/flood-preparedness/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insights into flood risk misperceptions of homeowners in the Dutch river delta</title>
      <link>/publication/mol-2020-b/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/mol-2020-b/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>After the virtual flood</title>
      <link>/project/after-the-vr-flood/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/after-the-vr-flood/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3&gt; After the virtual flood: risk perceptions, emotions and preparedness after flood risk communication in virtual reality  &lt;/h3&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;With 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://research.vu.nl/en/persons/wjw-botzen&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Wouter Botzen&lt;/a&gt; and 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://research.vu.nl/en/persons/julia-blasch&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Julia Blasch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Abstract:&lt;/b&gt;
Flooding is one of the most deathly and costly natural disasters in the world and its impacts are expected to increase due to increased urbanization in coastal areas and climate change. Effective risk communication may increase investments in voluntary damage reduction measures by individual homeowners. We know from previous survey research that the strongest predictors of flood preparedness are emotions, coping values and personal norms. Generally, homeowners with (recent) flood risk experience are better prepared, which is mediated through emotions and a better understanding of the consequences of flooding. This research uses high-immersive virtual reality technology to examine whether risk perception, coping appraisal, negative emotions and damage-reducing investment behavior can be enhanced through the experience of a virtual flood. We use a repeated measures design to examine (1) whether these effects last and (2) whether respondents have engaged in flood preparedness behavior at home by installing (more) measures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[registered report submitted, data collection scheduled]&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Social norms for flood preparedness</title>
      <link>/project/social-norms/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/social-norms/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3&gt; All by myself? Testing descriptive social norm-nudges to increase flood preparedness among homeowners &lt;/h3&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;With 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://research.vu.nl/en/persons/wjw-botzen&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Wouter Botzen&lt;/a&gt;, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://research.vu.nl/en/persons/julia-blasch&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Julia Blasch&lt;/a&gt;, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://riskcenter.wharton.upenn.edu/elissa-kranzler/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Elissa Kranzler&lt;/a&gt; and 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://oid.wharton.upenn.edu/profile/kunreuth/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Howard Kunreuther&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Abstract:&lt;/b&gt;
Social norms are rules of behavior that are commonly approved by society. Nudges based on social norms (norm-nudges) are compelling interventions compared to traditional interventions, but they have to be carefully designed to be effective. This paper adds to the growing literature on the effectiveness of norm-nudges by analyzing the effectiveness of different norm-nudge messages with varying transparency on individual flood preparedness. We test two empirical norm-nudge frames with a large sample in two European countries, to evaluate the possible interactions between norm-nudge effectiveness, individual characteristics and intercultural differences. We contrast these empirical norm-nudge treatments with a control treatment and a norm focusing treatment, where respondents are first asked to guess what other respondents would do, before making a decision relevant for their own payoff. We conclude with policy recommendations about norm-nudge messages in the context of communicating risk reduction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[revise &amp;amp; resubmit]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Working paper available 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://riskcenter.wharton.upenn.edu/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/Social-norms_Mol-etal.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Behavioral motivations for self-insurance under different disaster risk insurance schemes</title>
      <link>/publication/mol-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/mol-2018/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
