<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Jantsje Mol</title>
    <link>/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Jantsje Mol</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Jantsje Mol &amp;copy; {year}</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>After the virtual flood</title>
      <link>/project/after-the-vr-flood/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/after-the-vr-flood/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;h3&gt; After the virtual flood:
Risk perceptions, emotions and preparedness after flood risk communication in virtual reality.&lt;/h3&gt;
With &lt;a href=&#34;https://research.vu.nl/en/persons/wjw-botzen&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Wouter Botzen&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://research.vu.nl/en/persons/julia-blasch&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Julia Blasch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Abstract:&lt;/b&gt;
In progress&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[project in design phase]&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Social norms for flood preparedness</title>
      <link>/project/social-norms/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/social-norms/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;h3&gt; Improving individual flood preparedness decisions through social norms &lt;/h3&gt;
With &lt;a href=&#34;https://research.vu.nl/en/persons/wjw-botzen&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Wouter Botzen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://research.vu.nl/en/persons/julia-blasch&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Julia Blasch&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://riskcenter.wharton.upenn.edu/elissa-kranzler/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Elissa Kranzler&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://oid.wharton.upenn.edu/profile/kunreuth/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Howard Kunreuther&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Abstract:&lt;/b&gt;
Social norms are rules of behavior that are commonly approved by society. Nudges based on social norms (norm-nudges) are compelling interventions compared to traditional interventions, but they have to be carefully designed to be effective. This paper adds to the growing literature on the effectiveness of norm-nudges by analyzing the effectiveness of different norm-nudge messages with varying transparency on individual flood preparedness. We test two empirical norm-nudge frames with a large sample in two European countries, to evaluate the possible interactions between norm-nudge effectiveness, individual characteristics and intercultural differences. We contrast these empirical norm-nudge treatments with a control treatment and a norm focusing treatment, where respondents are first asked to guess what other respondents would do, before making a decision relevant for their own payoff. We conclude with policy recommendations about norm-nudge messages in the context of communicating risk reduction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[project in data analysis phase]&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The avocado paradox</title>
      <link>/project/avocado-paradox/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/avocado-paradox/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;h3&gt; The avocado paradox: Millennials&amp;rsquo; motivations and misconceptions of sustainable diets. &lt;/h3&gt;
With &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.meikemorren.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Meike Morren&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://research.vu.nl/en/persons/julia-blasch&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Julia Blasch&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://research.vu.nl/en/persons/%C5%BEiga-malek&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&amp;#381;iga Malek&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Abstract:&lt;/b&gt;
In the coming decades, society has to provide food security for the growing global population, while simultaneously shifting to healthier diets and decreasing humanity&amp;rsquo;s impact on the climate, freshwater and biodiversity. Demand side strategies for sustainable food production include the promotion of alternative diets. These dietary choices are often driven by various extrinsic and intrinsic motivations. Besides, many consumers have misconceptions about the environmental impact of food products as well as about what constitutes a &amp;lsquo;healthy diet&amp;rsquo;. A particularly relevant consumer group to shape the consumption patterns of the future are Millennials, who currently account for 27% of the world population and who grew up with alternative dietary choices like vegetarian and vegan diets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This paper aims to understand extrinsic and intrinsic motivations of Millennials&amp;rsquo; adoption of alternative diets and the extent to which misconceptions about healthy and sustainable food choices affect the adoption of alternative diets. To explore the drivers and misconceptions, we analyse self-reported diet, food-related price-sensitivity, health attitudes and environmental concern from an online survey among 305 Millennials. In a follow-up survey, 63 participants uploaded detailed information about five home-cooked meals. These barcodes and receipts were scored on the respective food products&amp;rsquo; impact on land-use and their wider environmental sustainability. Furthermore, we conducted 23 qualitative interviews with a diverse subsample to explore the underlying associations with food sustainability, and how the misconceptions guide dietary choices. Based on our results, policy interventions could be designed to stimulate the uptake of sustainable diets by this important group of consumers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[project in data analysis phase]&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
