<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects | Jantsje Mol</title>
    <link>https://www.jantsje.nl/project/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://www.jantsje.nl/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Projects</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Jantsje Mol © 2021</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://www.jantsje.nl/images/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://www.jantsje.nl/project/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>The importance of trust in the sharing economy</title>
      <link>https://www.jantsje.nl/project/trustpath/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jantsje.nl/project/trustpath/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3&gt; The importance of trust in the sharing economy &lt;/h3&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;With 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.uva.nl/en/profile/s/h/s.shalvi/s.shalvi.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Shaul Shalvi&lt;/a&gt;, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://sites.google.com/site/ivansoraperra/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Ivan Soraperra&lt;/a&gt;, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.uva.nl/en/profile/l/e/m.leib/m.leib.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Margarita Leib&lt;/a&gt;, 

&lt;a href=&#34;https://behavioralethics.org/author/linh-vu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Linh Vu&lt;/a&gt; and 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://behavioralethics.org/author/catherine-molho/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Catherine Molho&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Abstract:&lt;/b&gt;
The collaborative economy covers a variety of sectors and is rapidly emerging across Europe. Adding hundreds of billions of euro to the EU economy, it offers more choices to consumers and new opportunities to entrepreneurs. However, little is known about the bottom-up psychological factors driving the collaborative economy users’ behaviour. For responsible sharing, trust is necessary but not sufficient. The EU-funded TRUSTPATH project will develop and test a psychological theory of how people use the collaborative economy. The hypothesis is that trust encouraged without transparency can lead users to neglect the negative side effects trade has on others. The findings will advance our understanding of the psychology of the collaborative economy and inform policymakers seeking to regulate it. The results will also be useful for companies seeking to promote responsible sharing among users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information on the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://behavioralethics.org/project/trustpath/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Behavioral Ethics project website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>After the virtual flood</title>
      <link>https://www.jantsje.nl/project/after-the-vr-flood/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jantsje.nl/project/after-the-vr-flood/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3&gt; After the virtual flood: risk perceptions and flood preparedness after virtual reality risk communication  &lt;/h3&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;With 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://research.vu.nl/en/persons/wjw-botzen&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Wouter Botzen&lt;/a&gt; and 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://research.vu.nl/en/persons/julia-blasch&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Julia Blasch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Abstract:&lt;/b&gt;
Many individuals experience problems understanding and preparing for low-probability impact risk, like natural disasters and pandemics – unless they experience these events, yet then it is often too late to avoid damages. Individuals with recent disaster risk experience are, on average, better prepared. This seems to be mediated through emotions and a better understanding of the consequences. In this study, we use immersive virtual reality (VR) technology to examine whether a simulated disaster can stimulate people to invest in risk reducing measures in the context of flooding, which is one of the deathliest and most damaging natural disasters in the world. We investigate the possibility to boost risk perception, coping appraisal, negative emotions and damage-reducing behavior through a simulated flooding experience. An important novelty of the current set-up is that we examine the persistence of the effects by using a follow-up survey several weeks after the VR intervention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[in data analysis phase]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://player.vimeo.com/video/482506190&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;360&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;autoplay; fullscreen&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hurricane preparedness during the Covid-19 pandemic</title>
      <link>https://www.jantsje.nl/project/dorian-covid/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jantsje.nl/project/dorian-covid/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3&gt; Individual Hurricane Preparedness During the COVID-19 Pandemic: Insights for Risk Communication and Emergency Management Policies. &lt;/h3&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;With 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://research.vu.nl/en/persons/wjw-botzen&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Wouter Botzen&lt;/a&gt;, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://research.vu.nl/en/persons/peter-john-robinson&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Peter Robinson&lt;/a&gt;, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://sites.google.com/temple.edu/juan-zhang/home&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Juan Zhang&lt;/a&gt; and 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://media.iccsafe.org/2019_ICC_AnCon/docs/Bio_J_Czajkowski.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Jeffrey Czajkowski&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Abstract:&lt;/b&gt;
Climate change adaptation strategies should anticipate that the 2020 situation which resembles an above average hurricane season coinciding with a pandemic may occur more frequently in the future. This study draws lessons on how individual hurricane preparedness is influenced by a pandemic, which turns out to be a combination of perceptions of flood and pandemic risks that have opposite effects on preparedness behavior. We conducted three waves of surveys during 2019-2020 to monitor hurricane preparedness activities in flood-prone coastal areas in Florida, including a survey of 600 respondents in early June 2020 to obtain insights into households’ risk perceptions and preparedness for this hurricane season under COVID-19. The results show that this hurricane season is dominated by concerns over COVID-19 which influences people’s evacuation intentions. Whereas hotel costs were the main obstacle to evacuating during Hurricane Dorian in 2019, the main evacuation obstacle identified in the 2020 hurricane season is COVID-19. Our statistical analyses that investigates the factors influencing evacuation intentions consistently show that older individuals are less likely to evacuate voluntarily, because they are concerned about becoming infected by COVID-19. We discuss the implications of our findings for adaptation policies that aim to improve hurricane preparedness in situations of a pandemic, such as risk communication and emergency management policies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[in review]&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Changing diets</title>
      <link>https://www.jantsje.nl/project/avocado-paradox/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jantsje.nl/project/avocado-paradox/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3&gt; Changing diets - Testing the impact of knowledge and information nudges on sustainable dietary choices &lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.meikemorren.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Meike Morren&lt;/a&gt;, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://research.vu.nl/en/persons/julia-blasch&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Julia Blasch&lt;/a&gt; and 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://research.vu.nl/en/persons/%C5%BEiga-malek&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Žiga Malek&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Abstract:&lt;/b&gt;
A shift to more sustainable diets is needed to ensure food security and to reduce the pressure on the environment. Yet, many consumers have misconceptions about the environmental impacts of their diets and lack knowledge on how to prepare sustainable meals. This study uses a mixed-methods approach to develop four information nudges and to test their impact on dietary choices among a representative sample of Dutch consumers. A 2 X 2 between-subjects design crossing type of information (procedural versus declarative) with type of impacts (health versus environmental) is applied. The environmental impact is measured in terms of CO2 emissions, land use and water use. We find that pre-intervention knowledge about sustainable or healthy diets is related to the sustainability of participants&#39; dietary choices. Procedural knowledge on how to prepare a healthier meal has the greatest potential to influence dietary behavior, in particular for participants without prior self-reported dietary restrictions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[manuscript in review]&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Social norms for flood preparedness</title>
      <link>https://www.jantsje.nl/project/social-norms/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jantsje.nl/project/social-norms/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3&gt; All by myself? Testing descriptive social norm-nudges to increase flood preparedness among homeowners &lt;/h3&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;With 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://research.vu.nl/en/persons/wjw-botzen&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Wouter Botzen&lt;/a&gt;, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://research.vu.nl/en/persons/julia-blasch&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Julia Blasch&lt;/a&gt;, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://riskcenter.wharton.upenn.edu/elissa-kranzler/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Elissa Kranzler&lt;/a&gt; and 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://oid.wharton.upenn.edu/profile/kunreuth/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Howard Kunreuther&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Abstract:&lt;/b&gt;
Nudges based on social norms (norm-nudges) can be compelling behavioral interventions compared to traditional interventions such as taxes and regulations, but they do not work in all circumstances. We tested two empirical norm-nudge frames in an online experiment on taking measures for flood preparedness with large samples of homeowners (N = 1805) in two European countries, to evaluate the possible interactions between norm-nudge effectiveness, individual characteristics and intercultural differences. We contrasted these norm-nudge treatments with a control and norm focusing treatment by asking respondents to express their beliefs about what other respondents would do before making a decision relevant to their own payoff. We find no evidence of a treatment effect, suggesting that our social norm-nudges do not affect flood preparedness in the context of a flood risk investment game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[revise &amp;amp; resubmit]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Working paper available 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dx.doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.3616189&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
