<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects | Jantsje Mol</title>
    <link>https://www.jantsje.nl/project/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://www.jantsje.nl/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Projects</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Jantsje Mol © 2025</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://www.jantsje.nl/images/icon_hu7859828887360647904.png</url>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://www.jantsje.nl/project/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Educational perspective on Aquabots</title>
      <link>https://www.jantsje.nl/project/aquabots/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jantsje.nl/project/aquabots/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3&gt; An educational perspective on the Aquabots development platform for autonomous navigation &lt;/h3&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;With 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/peter-verheijen-96b8a1a&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Peter Verheijen&lt;/a&gt;, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/jan-smallegange-9996777/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Jan Smallegange&lt;/a&gt; and 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/jan-scholtens-93a316aa/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Jan Scholtens&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Abstract:&lt;/b&gt;
Aquabots is a development platform for autonomous navigation which was initiated in 2010 by the Rotterdam University of Applied Sciences and system integrator Imtech. In 2014, the first student team successfully crossed the river Nieuwe Maas with their Remotely Operated Vessel (Aquabot) EindMaas. By structuring the project as stacked research, where each team builds upon the work of their predecessors, significant time savings and deeper knowledge development have been achieved. This modular concept, starting from 2017, has enabled various, consecutive student teams to develop individual components of the system architecture. This approach ensured continuity, prevented knowledge loss, and allowed teams to focus on advancing the technology rather than redoing previous work. Over the years, as developments have progressed, it has become increasingly difficult to preserve and extend the knowledge base. To combat the major drawback of various consecutive student teams, a community system will be set up, which consists of teachers, company representatives and students who have contributed to the Aquabots project over the years. This will require active and fruitful cooperation and knowledge sharing, not only from the academic side (students plus teachers), but also from the business sector. In this way common resources as well as knowledge can accumulate, academic potential can be explored, and the related business sector will have access to building blocks which can be applied to exploit their business potential. We believe that the incubation phase of follow-up multidisciplinary student teams working on the Aquabots project can be shortened significantly. This paper documents best practices and challenges of such a modular learning community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[accepted for IEEE Symposium on Maritime Informatics &amp;amp; Robotics]&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Increasing trackpilot information load</title>
      <link>https://www.jantsje.nl/project/trackpilot-information-load/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jantsje.nl/project/trackpilot-information-load/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3&gt; Measuring situational awareness onboard and ashore under increasing trackpilot information load  &lt;/h3&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;With 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.hogeschoolrotterdam.nl/onderzoek/lectoren/coe-hrtech/lectoren/verduijn-thierry/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Thierry Verduijn&lt;/a&gt;, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/monique-van-der-drift-65908399/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Monique van der Drift&lt;/a&gt; and 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/andreea-s-pop-34b24970/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Andreea Pop&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Abstract:&lt;/b&gt;
Trackpilots can help inland shippers sail an optimal route with minimal human input, which has the potential to save fuel costs and human attention. In theory, widespread adoption of trackpilots is not only beneficial for crew on board, but also for traffic operators ashore, for example by minimizing verbal communication which could allow operators to focus on the most important safety concerns. However, a larger information load in the form of trackpilot data may not necessarily increase situational awareness. This paper examines the effect of trackpilots on situational awareness in practice, with two field experiments run by students of the Rotterdam University of Applied Sciences. The exploratory results suggest that a trackpilot has a positive effect on situational awareness and decreases workload on board. At the same time, when vessel traffic services (VTS) operators ashore receive trackpilot information, situational awareness is unaffected, but operators expect the workload to increase. Policy implications and suggestions for further research are discussed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[analysis phase]&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing a new hurricane scale</title>
      <link>https://www.jantsje.nl/project/testing-new-storm-scale/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jantsje.nl/project/testing-new-storm-scale/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3&gt; An experimental test of risk perceptions under a new hurricane classification system &lt;/h3&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;With 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://research.vu.nl/en/persons/nadia-bloemendaal&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Nadia Bloemendaal&lt;/a&gt;, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://research.vu.nl/en/persons/hans-de-moel&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Hans de Moel&lt;/a&gt;, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://sites.google.com/view/dianna-amasino/bio?authuser=0&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Dianna Amasino&lt;/a&gt; and 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.usf.edu/arts-sciences/departments/geosciences/people/faculty/jennifer-collins.aspx&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Jennifer Collins&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Abstract:&lt;/b&gt;
During a hurricane, it is vital that individuals receive communications that are easy to process and provide sufficient information to allow informed hurricane preparedness decisions and prevent loss of life. We study how the hurricane warning scale (traditional Saffir-Simpson Hurricane Wind Scale versus the newly developed 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jantsje.nl/publication/bloemendaal-2020/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Tropical Cyclone Severity Scale&lt;/a&gt;) impacts intent to evacuate and understanding of hurricane severity. We use a between-subject design where participants are assigned to either the traditional SSHWS or the new TCSS scale. We will collect data in a large-scale (~4000 participants) online experiment to examine potential differences in comprehension, risk perception, anticipated evacuation and preparation decisions among residents in U.S. coastal states prone to hurricanes. We test the hypotheses that the new scale increases understanding about the main hazard, increases evacuation intent for severe events, and increases relevant precautionary measures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[in-conditional-acceptance at Scientific Reports]&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Giving as a self-control problem</title>
      <link>https://www.jantsje.nl/project/giving-self-control/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jantsje.nl/project/giving-self-control/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3&gt; Giving as a self-control problem &lt;/h3&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;With 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://tinbergen.nl/person/1775/cristina-figueroa&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Cristina Figueroa&lt;/a&gt;, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://sites.google.com/site/ivansoraperra/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Ivan Soraperra&lt;/a&gt; and 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.joelvanderweele.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Joel van der Weele&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Abstract:&lt;/b&gt;
Social preferences depend on emotional states like compassion and anger. Since emotions are fleeting and subject to manipulation, they may generate demand for commitment. We investigate the use of commitment strategies in an online experiment (n = 1,400), where subjects decide to watch or avoid videos before engaging in a charitable giving task. We find that a video with emotional content increases giving, but is also avoided more than non-emotional videos. We estimate a structural model of state-dependent social preferences, and show evidence for sophisticated commitment to selfishness and altruism. We argue that giving can be fruitfully analyzed as a self-control problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[submitted]&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Information design in one-sided matching problems</title>
      <link>https://www.jantsje.nl/project/task-matching/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jantsje.nl/project/task-matching/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3&gt; For the &#39;Greater Good&#39;: Please Choose A&lt;/h3&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;With 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.lenkafiala.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Lenka Fiala&lt;/a&gt; and 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://sites.google.com/view/sulagna/home?authuser=0&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Sulagna Dasgupta&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Abstract:&lt;/b&gt;
How do people trade off individual versus group welfare in the face of uncertainty regarding private benefits of different actions? We propose a partial information revelation (`recommendation&amp;rsquo;) policy  designed to maximize group welfare, and we show its theoretical robustness to well-documented behavioral deviations from the risk neutral, Bayesian, and self-interested benchmark. In a large-scale online experiment with 2600 subjects, we then show that this policy fails to improve upon a full information benchmark even when individual and group objectives are aligned. In this case, information design is theoretically powerful but requires sophisticated inferences from players. Indeed, we show that cognitive limitations reduce the predictive value of the theory. This provides suggestive evidence in favor of simplicity in information design in multi-agent strategic settings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[in review]&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
