<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects | Jantsje Mol</title>
    <link>/project/</link>
      <atom:link href="/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Projects</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Jantsje Mol © 2020</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/images/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/project/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tropical Cyclone Severity Scale</title>
      <link>/project/tropical-cyclones/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/tropical-cyclones/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3&gt; Adequately reflecting the severity of tropical cyclones using the new Tropical Cyclone Severity Scale. &lt;/h3&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;With 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://research.vu.nl/en/persons/nadia-bloemendaal&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Nadia Bloemendaal&lt;/a&gt;, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://research.vu.nl/en/persons/hans-de-moel&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Hans de Moel&lt;/a&gt;, Priscilla Bosma, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.usf.edu/honors/about-us/amypolen.aspx&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Amy Polen&lt;/a&gt; and 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://hennarot.forest.usf.edu/main/depts/geosci/faculty/jcollins/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Jennifer Collins&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Abstract:&lt;/b&gt;
For decades, meteorologists and governments have been warning communities in coastal areas for an imminent tropical cyclone (TC) using the Saffir-Simpson Hurricane Wind Scale (SSHWS). The SSHWS categorizes a TC based on its maximum wind speeds, and is used in defining evacuation strategies and humanitarian response. However, the SSHWS considers only wind hazard, whereas a TC can also cause severe conditions through its high storm surges and extreme rainfall, triggering coastal and inland flooding. Consequently, the SSHWS fails to mirror the TC’s total severity. This becomes evident when looking at past events such as Hurricane Harvey (2017), which was classified as a Tropical Storm while it caused widespread flooding in the Houston (TX) area, with precipitation totals exceeding 1.5 m. With the absence of storm surge and rainfall, adequate risk communication with the SSHWS can be challenging, as the public can (mistakenly) perceive a low-category TC as a low-risk TC. To overcome this, we propose the new Tropical Cyclone Severity Scale (TCSS) that includes all three major TC hazards in its classification. The new scale preserves the categorization as used in the SSHWS, to maintain familiarity amongst the general public. In addition, to support communication about the most extreme TCs, we extend the TCSS with a Category 6. While the SSHWS is currently used to communicate about the total event severity, the TCSS is primarily designed to be applied on a local-scale, hereby supporting local-scale risk communication efforts and evacuation strategies prior to a TC landfall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[revise &amp;amp; resubmit]&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>After the virtual flood</title>
      <link>/project/after-the-vr-flood/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/after-the-vr-flood/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3&gt; After the virtual flood: risk perceptions, emotions and preparedness after flood risk communication in virtual reality  &lt;/h3&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;With 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://research.vu.nl/en/persons/wjw-botzen&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Wouter Botzen&lt;/a&gt; and 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://research.vu.nl/en/persons/julia-blasch&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Julia Blasch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Abstract:&lt;/b&gt;
Flooding is one of the most deathly and costly natural disasters in the world and its impacts are expected to increase due to increased urbanization in coastal areas and climate change. Effective risk communication may increase investments in voluntary damage reduction measures by individual homeowners. We know from previous survey research that the strongest predictors of flood preparedness are emotions, coping values and personal norms. Generally, homeowners with (recent) flood risk experience are better prepared, which is mediated through emotions and a better understanding of the consequences of flooding. This research uses high-immersive virtual reality technology to examine whether risk perception, coping appraisal, negative emotions and damage-reducing investment behavior can be enhanced through the experience of a virtual flood. We use a repeated measures design to examine (1) whether these effects last and (2) whether respondents have engaged in flood preparedness behavior at home by installing (more) measures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[registered report submitted, data collection scheduled]&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Changing diets</title>
      <link>/project/avocado-paradox/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/avocado-paradox/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3&gt; Changing diets - Testing the impact of knowledge and information nudges on sustainable dietary choices &lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.meikemorren.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Meike Morren&lt;/a&gt;, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://research.vu.nl/en/persons/julia-blasch&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Julia Blasch&lt;/a&gt; and 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://research.vu.nl/en/persons/%C5%BEiga-malek&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Žiga Malek&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Abstract:&lt;/b&gt;
A shift to more sustainable diets is needed to ensure food security and to reduce the pressure on the environment. Yet, many consumers have misconceptions about the environmental impacts of their diets and lack knowledge on how to prepare sustainable meals. This study uses a mixed-methods approach to develop four information nudges and to test their impact on dietary choices among a representative sample of Dutch consumers. A 2 X 2 between-subjects design crossing type of information (procedural versus declarative) with type of impacts (health versus environmental) is applied. The environmental impact is measured in terms of CO2 emissions, land use and water use. We find that pre-intervention knowledge about sustainable or healthy diets is related to the sustainability of participants&amp;rsquo; dietary choices. Procedural knowledge on how to prepare a healthier meal has the greatest potential to influence dietary behavior, in particular for participants without prior self-reported dietary restrictions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[manuscript submitted]&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Social norms for flood preparedness</title>
      <link>/project/social-norms/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/social-norms/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3&gt; All by myself? Testing descriptive social norm-nudges to increase flood preparedness among homeowners &lt;/h3&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;With 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://research.vu.nl/en/persons/wjw-botzen&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Wouter Botzen&lt;/a&gt;, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://research.vu.nl/en/persons/julia-blasch&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Julia Blasch&lt;/a&gt;, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://riskcenter.wharton.upenn.edu/elissa-kranzler/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Elissa Kranzler&lt;/a&gt; and 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://oid.wharton.upenn.edu/profile/kunreuth/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Howard Kunreuther&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Abstract:&lt;/b&gt;
Social norms are rules of behavior that are commonly approved by society. Nudges based on social norms (norm-nudges) are compelling interventions compared to traditional interventions, but they have to be carefully designed to be effective. This paper adds to the growing literature on the effectiveness of norm-nudges by analyzing the effectiveness of different norm-nudge messages with varying transparency on individual flood preparedness. We test two empirical norm-nudge frames with a large sample in two European countries, to evaluate the possible interactions between norm-nudge effectiveness, individual characteristics and intercultural differences. We contrast these empirical norm-nudge treatments with a control treatment and a norm focusing treatment, where respondents are first asked to guess what other respondents would do, before making a decision relevant for their own payoff. We conclude with policy recommendations about norm-nudge messages in the context of communicating risk reduction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[revise &amp;amp; resubmit]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Working paper available 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://riskcenter.wharton.upenn.edu/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/Social-norms_Mol-etal.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
