<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects | Jantsje Mol</title>
    <link>https://www.jantsje.nl/project/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://www.jantsje.nl/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Projects</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Jantsje Mol © 2021</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://www.jantsje.nl/images/icon_hue4a4de327998694cb345fdb70473462a_27719_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://www.jantsje.nl/project/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Supply of willful ignorance</title>
      <link>https://www.jantsje.nl/project/the-button/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jantsje.nl/project/the-button/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3&gt; You wouldn&#39;t want to know. Experimental evidence about the supply of willful ignorance in a simple button game &lt;/h3&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;With 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.uva.nl/en/profile/s/h/s.shalvi/s.shalvi.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Shaul Shalvi&lt;/a&gt;, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://sites.google.com/site/ivansoraperra/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Ivan Soraperra&lt;/a&gt; and 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://sites.google.com/site/joelvdweele/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Joël van der Weele&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Abstract:&lt;/b&gt;
Many people would rather not tell their friends that their decisions can negatively affect a third party, for example by explaining the environmental harm of meat consumption. This paper examines under which circumstances people are willing to interfere by sharing or hiding information: in other words, the supply of willful ignorance. We use a simple online experiment to explore three possible concerns in this situation: own payoffs, charity payoffs and concerns about the decision maker. We developed a new two-person sender-receiver game in which the Receiver decides between a default option with fixed payoffs for self and charity versus an alternative which yields a slightly higher payoff to self, but uncertain payoffs for charity. Senders can send a message with the true value of charity payoff, or suppress such inconvenient information to ‘help’ decision makers staying ignorant. We measure the impact of the three concerns and their relationships with different treatments in a large pre-registered online experiment, controlling for charity preference and the size of the externality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[in design phase]&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Information design in matching problems</title>
      <link>https://www.jantsje.nl/project/task-matching/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jantsje.nl/project/task-matching/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3&gt; Information design in matching problems: Evidence from an online experiment &lt;/h3&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;With 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.lenkafiala.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Lenka Fiala&lt;/a&gt; and 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://sites.google.com/view/sulagna/home?authuser=0&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Sulagna Dasgupta&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Abstract:&lt;/b&gt;
In one-sided matching settings such as school choice and task allocation, objects are allocated to agents based on agent preferences. However, agents may not always know, a priori, their preferences over the objects, because they do not have enough information. In this context, we experimentally investigate the question: How should a benevolent planner optimally reveal information to the agents to maximize welfare? To this end, we conduct an online experiment to test the theoretical predictions of 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/file/d/1yedWFi3ijiKn9zaFUU8BQPFjy-iwAc2l/view&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Dasgupta (2020)&lt;/a&gt; who proposes recommendations, and identify behavioral explanations in case of a possible mismatch between model and behavior in the experiment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[in testing phase]&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing a new hurricane scale</title>
      <link>https://www.jantsje.nl/project/testing-new-storm-scale/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jantsje.nl/project/testing-new-storm-scale/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3&gt; An experimental test of risk perceptions under a new hurricane classification system &lt;/h3&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;With 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://research.vu.nl/en/persons/nadia-bloemendaal&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Nadia Bloemendaal&lt;/a&gt; and 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://research.vu.nl/en/persons/julia-blasch&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Amy Polen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Abstract:&lt;/b&gt;
During a hurricane, it is vital that individuals receive communications that are easy to process and provide sufficient information to allow informed hurricane evacuation decisions and prevent loss of life. Without satisfactory and complete information, an individual is likely to miscalculate their personal risk or even potentially be moved to inaction. However, much recent research has shown an over-reliance on the currently-utilized Saffir-Simpson Hurricane Wind Scale (SSHWS) despite the fact that it only captures one aspect of a hurricane: the wind threat. Communications campaigns have been attempting to bridge this divide by providing additional information, but the importance of a category cannot be escaped. As such, researchers have begun to formulate more holistic hurricane classification systems that account for water-based hazards, the biggest killer in hurricane events. These scales have not been previously tested on a large scale to determine their usability and clarity as a practical risk communication tool. This study will observe the efficacy of the Tropical Cyclone Severity Scale, or TCSS 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jantsje.nl/publication/bloemendaal-2020/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Bloemendaal et al., 2021&lt;/a&gt;, in practice and its viability as a wide-reaching communications tool. Utilizing surveys and online experiments, we will identify potential differences in comprehension, risk perception, and anticipated evacuation decisions between the current SSHWS and the new TCSS. The information gained from this study will be leveraged to influence emergency planning and risk communication in the formation of a nationwide scale that best serves the public.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[in design phase]&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meat opinions</title>
      <link>https://www.jantsje.nl/project/meat-opinions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jantsje.nl/project/meat-opinions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3&gt; Meat opinions - Exploring unconscious reasons for resistance towards a plant-based diet  &lt;/h3&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;With 
&lt;a href=&#34;www.meikemorren.com&#34;&gt;Meike Morren&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Abstract:&lt;/b&gt;
Despite the increased availability of plant-based products, a large group of consumers eats meat and dairy every day, unaware of the impact on environment and health. Increasing awareness is important, but ineffective without procedural knowledge (such as recipes) on how to change this diet. Furthermore, the global challenge to provide sustainable food security to a growing population cannot be tackled by a focus on consumers who are already transitioning to a plant-based diet. This project targets the heaviest meat-eaters and tests the most effective way to make them part of the solution. Despite the evident benefits, many people do not even consider changing to a plant-based diet and meat, dairy and egg consumption continues to increase worldwide. These consumers likely ignore information as it does not align with their beliefs. 
We will obtain insights into the origins of resistance towards a plant-based diet using in-depth interviews and text mining of blogs, pod casts and internet forums. We will gather podcast transcripts, reviews and remarks about meat versus plant-based diets posed on fora such as Quora through web scraping. This way, we will create a database of texts (i.e. referred to as documents) in which the underlying resistance towards a plant-based diet is discussed openly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, we will identify the topics being discussed repeatedly across the collected documents using an unsupervised machine learning model such as Latent Dirichlet Allocation (Blei et al., 2003). LDA allows us to gather topics that are mentioned in multiple documents. Next, using advanced natural language processing models, such as BERT (Devlin et al., 2018), and recent advances such as GoEmotions (Demszky et al., 2021) we will attempt to discover the emotions underlying a resistance towards a plant-based diet. Finally, we will survey the general population to examine the interplay of current diet, emotions and arguments for underlying resistance to transition to a plant-based diet. We will apply a novel method that we recently developed to measure actual environmental impacts of current diet (Morren et al., 2021). This method is suitable for internet-based surveys in the general population.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our research aims to explain why certain people resist a plant-based diet. As meat-eaters are responsible for a large share of environmental impacts, there is a lot to be gained. We will deliver specific recommendations to policy makers about the most promising type of message to encourage heavy meat-eaters to transition to a plant-based diet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[in data collection phase]&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The importance of trust in the sharing economy</title>
      <link>https://www.jantsje.nl/project/trustpath/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jantsje.nl/project/trustpath/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3&gt; The importance of trust in the sharing economy &lt;/h3&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;With 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.uva.nl/en/profile/s/h/s.shalvi/s.shalvi.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Shaul Shalvi&lt;/a&gt;, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://sites.google.com/site/ivansoraperra/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Ivan Soraperra&lt;/a&gt;, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.uva.nl/en/profile/l/e/m.leib/m.leib.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Margarita Leib&lt;/a&gt;, 

&lt;a href=&#34;https://behavioralethics.org/author/linh-vu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Linh Vu&lt;/a&gt; and 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://behavioralethics.org/author/catherine-molho/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Catherine Molho&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Abstract:&lt;/b&gt;
The collaborative economy covers a variety of sectors and is rapidly emerging across Europe. Adding hundreds of billions of euro to the EU economy, it offers more choices to consumers and new opportunities to entrepreneurs. However, little is known about the bottom-up psychological factors driving the collaborative economy users’ behaviour. For responsible sharing, trust is necessary but not sufficient. The EU-funded TRUSTPATH project will develop and test a psychological theory of how people use the collaborative economy. The hypothesis is that trust encouraged without transparency can lead users to neglect the negative side effects trade has on others. The findings will advance our understanding of the psychology of the collaborative economy and inform policymakers seeking to regulate it. The results will also be useful for companies seeking to promote responsible sharing among users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information on the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://behavioralethics.org/project/trustpath/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Behavioral Ethics project website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
